Guide to the Bonnie Campbell Papers, 2000-2016 RL.11496
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Bonnie Campbell papers
2000-2016
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Campbell, Bonnie
RL.11496
3 Linear Feet 4 boxes
Printed materials, advertisements, and publications designed by Bonnie Campbell, former Art Director at the Center for Documentary Studies at Duke University.
Biographical / Historical
Former art director at the Center for Documentary Studies, Duke University.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Bonnie Campbell Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2017.
Related Materials
Many of the CDS projects and publications represented here are also searchable in the catalog.
Collection Overview
Collection consists of printed materials and publications designed by Bonnie Campbell during 16 years as Art Director at the Center for Documentary Studies. Campbell's work included designing promotional and marketing materials, such as postcards, posters, and brochures, for many CDS programs and projects including their Duke curriculum programs, community programs, exhibits, and awards series. Campbell also designed several CDS publications, including Document, the center's newsletter, along with photography books Beyond Beauty: Photographs from the Archive of Documentary Arts, One Place: Paul Kwilecki and Four Decades of Photographs (Paul Kwilecki), Sodom Laurel Album (Rob Amberg), and In This Timeless Time (Bruce Jackson).
Documentary photography; Archive of Documentary Arts (Duke University); Duke University. Center for Documentary Studies; Duke University -- Employees
- Center for Documentary Studies promotional materials, 2001-2016; 1
  - General CDS publicity, undated (Box 1)
  - Advertisements, 2008-2016 (Box 1)
  - General promotional materials for events, 2001-2016 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Postcards, posters, and other promotional pieces produced by Campbell. Text written and edited by Lynn McKnight, Liz Phillips, and Alexa Dilworth.
  - General promotional materials for events, 2007-2008 and undated (Box 3)
    Promotional posters
  - Documentary Forum, 2015 (Box 1)
    Documentary Forum 2015 materials, produced by Campbell; written by Lynn McKnight, Liz Phillips, and Alexa Dilworth.
  - Exhibits at CDS, 2001-2017; 3 folders (Box 1)
    Postcards, posters, brochures, and printed matter created by the CDS Communications team to promote exhibits at the CDS. Produced by Campbell; CDS Communications Director Liz Phillips; and other members of the team including Alexa Dilworth and Lynn McKnight.
  - Exhibits at CDS, 2002-2017 (Box 3)
    Posters
  - Traveling exhibits, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Undergraduate program, certificates, undated (Box 1)
  - Undergraduate program, 2008 (Box 3)
    Poster
  - Continuing education programs, 2004-2016 (Box 1)
    Posters, booklets, brochures produced for the Continuing Education Program; produced by Campbell, written and edited by Marc Maximov, Liz Phillips, and Alexa Dilworth.
  - CDS programs: Audiovisual Materials, 2004-2010 and undated (Box 2)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Original audiovisual materials are closed to use. Contact Research Services in advance of your visit to request the production of listening or use copies.
    - Documentary Video Institute, 2004 (Box 2, Dvd RL-11496-DVD-0001)
    - Shared Pathways: Collaboration and Community in Southwest Central Durham (Documentary Video Institute), 2005 (Box 2, Dvd RL-11496-DVD-0002)
    - Shared Pathways: Collaboration and Community in Southwest Central Durham (Documentary Video Institute), 2006 (Box 2, Dvd RL-11496-DVD-0003)
    - Scene on Radio: The Sound of Life Happening podcast, undated (Box 2, Audio-cd RL-11496-CD-0001)
    - Travels with Mike: In Search of America 50 Years After Steinbeck, undated (Box 2, Audio-cd RL-11496-CD-0002)
    - Environmentally Themed Stories from the Triangle, 2010 July (Box 2, Audio-cd RL-11496-CD-0003)
    - CDS Radio Sampler: Montage from Recent Projects / Living Together/Living Apart, undated (Box 2, Audio-cd RL-11496-CD-0004)
  - Awards, 2001-2016 (Box 1)
    Posters, brochures, booklets, and postcards produced by CDS/Honickman First Book Prize in Photography and the Lange-Taylor Prize. Produced by Campbell; written and edited by Iris Tillman Hill and Alexa Dilworth.
  - Community projects, 2000s (Box 1)
  - Literacy through Photography, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Indivisible, 2001 (Box 2)
    "Putting Documentary Work to Work" guidebooks (in English and Spanish)
  - Face Up Project (Durham murals), undated (Box 2)
  - MFA/EDU program, 2011-2013 (Box 2)
  - Power Plant Gallery, 2013-2014 (Box 2)
  - Hine Documentary Fellows, undated (Box 2)
- Center for Documentary Studies publications, 2000-2016; 2
  - Promotional postcards and brochures for books, 2001-2016 (Box 2)
    Produced by Campbell.
  - Amberg, Rob: Sodom Laurel Album, 2002 (Box 3)
    Proofs
  - Beyond Beauty: The Archive of Documentary Arts at Duke University, 2008-2009; 2 folders (Box 2)
    Cover mockups, design iterations, and page proofs for Beyond Beauty. Editor: Andrew Armacost; Text editor: Bridget Booher; Images editor: Margaret Sartor; Book designer: Bonnie Campbell; Digital imaging: Mike Adamo.
  - Beyond Beauty: The Archive of Documentary Arts at Duke University, 2009 (Box 3)
    Blue line proofs
  - Jackson, Bruce: In This Timeless Time: Living and Dying on Death Row in America, 2012 (Box 2)
    Proofs for In This Timeless Time. Author/photographer: Bruce Jackson and Diane Christian. Editors: Tom Rankin and Iris Tillman Hill. Designer: Bonnie Campbell. Digital Imaging: Mike Adamo.
  - Jackson, Bruce: In This Timeless Time: Living and Dying on Death Row in America, 2012 (Box 3)
    Proofs, cover
  - Kwilecki, Paul: One Place: Paul Kwilecki and Four Decades of Photographs, 2013 (Box 2)
    Blad, F and Gs of book pages for One Place. Edited with foreword: Tom Rankin. Co-edited: Iris Tillman Hill. Book designer: Bonnie Campbell. Text editor: Alexa Dilworth.
  - Kwilecki, Paul: One Place: Paul Kwilecki and Four Decades of Photographs, 2012-2013; 2 folders (Box 3)
    Editorial proofs, cover designs, book jacket
  - Document newsletter, 2000-2016; 5 folders (Box 4)
    40 issues of the CDS newsletter Document, a quarterly publication featuring documentary work supported and produced by the CDS. Designed by Campbell. Edited by various people: Lynn McKnight, Alexa Dilworth, Lauren Hart, and Liz Phillips.